The following content is provided
提供以下内容
under a Creative Commons license.
根据知识共享许可。
Your support will help MIT OpenCourseWare continue
您的支持将帮助MIT OpenCourseWare继续
to offer high quality educational resources for free.
免费提供高质量的教育资源。
To make a donation or view additional materials
捐款或查看其他材料
from hundreds of MIT courses, visit MIT OpenCourseWare
从数百门麻省理工学院的课程中，访问MIT OpenCourseWare
at ocw.mit.edu.
在ocw.mit.edu。
PROFESSOR: All right.
教授：好的。
Let's get started.
让我们开始吧。
Today we start a brand new section of 006,
今天我们开始一个全新的006部分
which is hashing.
这是哈希。
Hashing is cool.
哈希很酷。
It is probably the most used and common and important
它可能是最常用，最常见和最重要的
data structure and all of computer science.
数据结构和所有计算机科学。
It's in, basically, every system you've ever used, I think.
我认为，基本上，它位于您曾经使用过的每个系统中。
And in particular, it's in Python
特别是在Python中
as part of what makes Python fun to program in.
是使Python有趣编程的一部分。
And basically, every modern programming language has it.
基本上，每种现代编程语言都有它。
So today is about how to make it actually happen.
所以今天是关于如何使其真正实现的。
So what is it?
那是什么
It is usually called a dictionary.
它通常被称为字典。
So this is an abstract data if you
所以这是一个抽象数据
remember that term from a couple lectures ago.
记得之前几次演讲中的那个词。
It's kind of an old term, not so common anymore,
这是一个古老的名词，不再常见了，
but it's useful to think about.
但是考虑一下很有用。
So a dictionary is a data structure,
因此，字典是一种数据结构，
or it's a thing, that can store items,
或者是可以存储物品的东西，
and it can insert items, delete items and search for items.
它可以插入项目，删除项目和搜索项目。
So in general, it's going to be a set of items,
所以总的来说，它将是一组项目，
each item has a key.
每个项目都有一个钥匙。
And you can insert an item, you can delete an item
您可以插入一个项目，也可以删除一个项目
from the set, and you can search for a key, not an item.
从集合中，您可以搜索密钥，而不是项目。
And the interesting part is the search.
有趣的部分是搜索。
I think you know what insert and delete do.
我想您知道插入和删除的作用。
So there are two outcomes to this kind of search.
因此，这种搜索有两个结果。
This is what I call an exact search.
这就是我所说的精确搜索。
Either you find an item with a given key, or there isn't one,
您是否找到了具有给定键的项，或者没有，
and then you just say key error in Python.
然后您只说Python中的关键错误。
OK.
好。
This is a little different from what
这与
we could do with binary search trees.
我们可以使用二叉搜索树。
Binary search trees, if we didn't find a key,
二进制搜索树，如果我们找不到键，
we could find the next larger and the next smaller
我们可以找到下一个更大的和下一个较小的
successor and predecessor.
后继者和前任者。
With dictionaries you're not allowed to do that,
使用字典，您将无法这样做，
or you're not able to do that.
否则您将无法做到。
And you're just interested in the question
您只是对这个问题感兴趣
does the key exist?
钥匙是否存在？
And if so, give me the item with that key.
如果是这样，请给我带有该钥匙的物品。
So we're assuming here that the items have unique keys,
因此，我们在这里假设项目具有唯一键，
no two items have the same key.
没有两个项目具有相同的密钥。
And one way to enforce that is when
一种实施方法是
you insert an item with an existing key,
您插入具有现有密钥的项目，
it overwrites whatever key was there.
它会覆盖那里的任何密钥。
That's the Python behavior.
这就是Python的行为。
So we'll assume that.
所以我们假设。
Overwrite any existing key.
覆盖任何现有密钥。
And so, it's well defined what search does.
因此，定义明确了搜索的作用。
Either there's one item with that key,
要么有一个带有那个钥匙的物品，
or there's no item with that key,
或没有带有该钥匙的物品，
and it tells you what the situation is.
它告诉您情况如何。
OK.
好。
So one way to solve dictionaries is
所以解决字典的一种方法是
to use a balanced binary search tree like AVL trees.
使用像AVL树这样的平衡二叉搜索树。
And so you can do all of these operations on log n time.
因此，您可以在登录n时执行所有这些操作。
I mean, you can ignore the fact that AVL trees give you
我的意思是，您可以忽略AVL树为您提供的事实
more information when you do a search,
搜索时获得更多信息，
and still does exact search.
并且仍会进行精确搜索。
So that's one solution, but it turns out you can do better.
因此，这是一种解决方案，但事实证明您可以做得更好。
And while last class was about, well, in the comparison model
虽然最后一堂课是关于比较模型的
the best way to sort is n log n and the best way to search
最好的排序方式是n log n和最好的搜索方式
is log n.
是日志n。
Then we saw in the RAM model, where
然后我们在RAM模型中看到
if you assume your items are integers we can sort faster,
如果您假设您的商品是整数，我们可以更快地进行排序，
sometimes we can sort in linear time.
有时我们可以按线性时间排序。
Today's lecture is about how to search faster than log n time.
今天的讲座是关于如何以比登录时间更快的速度进行搜索。
And we're going to get down to constant time.
而我们将要走到恒定的时间。
No-- basically, no assumptions except, maybe,
不，基本上没有任何假设，也许
that your keys are integers.
您的键是整数。
We'll be able to get down to constant time
我们将能够走到恒定的时间
with high probability.
可能性很高。
It's going to be a randomized data structure.
这将是一个随机的数据结构。
It's one of the few instances of randomization in 006,
这是006年为数不多的随机化实例之一，
but it'll be pretty simple to analyze, so don't worry.
但是分析起来非常简单，所以不用担心。
But we're going to use some probability today.
但是我们今天要使用一些概率。
Make it a little exciting.
让它变得令人兴奋。
I think you know how dictionaries work in Python.
我想您知道字典在Python中是如何工作的。
In Python it's the dict data type.
在Python中，它是dict数据类型。
We've used it all over the place.
我们在整个地方都用过它。
The key things you can do are lookup a key
您可以做的关键事情是查找关键
and-- so this is the analog of search--
并且-这就是搜索的类似物-
you can set a key to a value.
您可以将键设置为值。
This is the analog of an insert.
这是插入的类似物。
It overwrites whatever was there.
它会覆盖那里的所有内容。
And what else?
还有什么？
Delete.
删除。
So you can delete a particular key.
因此，您可以删除特定的密钥。
OK.
好。
We'll usually use this notation because it's
我们通常会使用这种表示法，因为
more familiar and intuitive.
更熟悉和直观。
But the big topic today is how do you actually
但是今天最重要的话题是
implement these operations for a dictionary, D?
为字典实现这些操作，D？
The one specific thing about Python dictionaries
关于Python词典的一件事
is that an item is basically a pair
基本上是一对
of two things, a key and a value.
两件事，一个键和一个值。
And so, in particular, when you call d.items
因此，尤其是当您调用d.items时
you get a whole bunch of ordered pairs, a key and a value.
您会得到一大堆有序的对，一个键和一个值。
And so the key is always-- the key of an item
因此，关键永远是项目的关键
is always this first part.
始终是第一部分。
So it's well defined.
因此，它定义明确。
OK.
好。
So that's Python dictionaries.
这就是Python字典。
So one obvious motivation for building dictionaries
因此，建立字典的一个明显动机
is you need them in Python.
您在Python中需要它们吗？
And in fact, people use them all the time.
实际上，人们一直在使用它们。
We used them in docdist.
我们在docdist中使用了它们。
All of the fastest versions of the document distance problem
所有最快版本的文档距离问题
used dictionaries for counting words, how many times each word
用字典来计数单词，每个单词多少次
occurs in a document, and for computing inner products,
出现在文档中，对于计算内部产品，
for finding common words between two documents.
查找两个文档之间的常用词。
And it's just it's the best way to do things,
这是做事的最好方法，
it's the easiest way to do things , and the fastest.
这是做事的最简单方法，也是最快的方法。
As a result, dictionaries are built into basically every
结果，基本上每个字典都内置了字典
modern programming language, Python, Perl, Ruby, JavaScript,
现代编程语言，Python，Perl，Ruby，JavaScript，
Java, C++, C#.
Java，C ++，C＃。
In modern versions, all have some version of dictionaries.
在现代版本中，所有版本都有一些版本的词典。
And they all run in, basically, constant time
它们基本上都在恒定的时间内运行
using the stuff that's in this lecture and the next two
使用本讲座中的内容以及接下来的两个
lectures.
讲座。
Let's see.
让我们来看看。
It's also, in, basically, every database.
基本上，它也在每个数据库中。
There are essentially two kinds of databases in the world,
世界上基本上有两种数据库，
there are those that use hashing,
有些使用散列，
and there are those that use search trees.
还有一些使用搜索树的网站。
Sometimes you need one.
有时您需要一个。
Sometimes you need the other.
有时您需要另一个。
There are a lot of situations in databases where you just
数据库中有很多情况，
need hashing.
需要哈希。
So if you've ever used Berkeley DB,
因此，如果您曾经使用过Berkeley DB，
there's a hash type of a database.
数据库的哈希类型。
So if things like, when you go to Merriam-Webster,
因此，如果发生类似情况，当您去Merriam-Webster时，
and you look up a word, how do you
你抬头一句话，你怎么样
find the definition of that word?
找到那个词的定义？
You use a hash table, you use a dictionary, I should say.
我应该说，您使用哈希表，使用字典。
How do you-- when you spell check your document,
您如何-拼写检查文件时，
how do you tell whether a word is correctly spelled?
您如何判断一个单词的拼写是否正确？
You look it up in a dictionary.
您在字典中查找它。
If it's not correctly spelled, how
如果拼写不正确，如何
do you find the closest related, correct spelling?
您找到最接近的相关正确拼写吗？
You try tweaking one the letters,
您尝试调整一个字母，
and look it up in a dictionary and see if it's there.
并在字典中查找它是否存在。
You do that for all possible letters, or maybe two letters.
您对所有可能的字母或两个字母执行此操作。
That is a state of the art way to do spelling correction.
这是进行拼写校正的最新方式。
Just keep looking up in a dictionary.
只是继续查字典。
Because dictionaries are so fast you
因为字典这么快，你
can afford to do things like trial perturbations of letters.
有能力做一些尝试，例如对信件进行骚扰。
What else.
还有什么。
In the old days, which means pre-Google,
在过去，这意味着在Google之前，
every search engine on the web would
网络上的每个搜索引擎都会
have a dictionary that says, for given word,
有一本字典说，对于给定的单词，
give me all of the documents containing that word.
给我所有包含该词的文件。
Google doesn't do it that way, but that's another story.
Google不会那样做，但这是另一回事。
It's less fancy, actually.
实际上，它不那么花哨。
Or when you log into a system, you
或者，当您登录系统时，
type your username and password.
输入您的用户名和密码。
You look in a dictionary that stores a username
您在存储用户名的字典中查找
and, associated with that username,
并且与该用户名相关联，
all the information of that user.
该用户的所有信息。
Every time you log into a web system, or whatever,
每次您登录网络系统时，
it is going through a dictionary.
它正在通过字典。
So they're all over the place.
所以他们到处都是。
One of the original applications is
原始应用之一是
in writing programming languages.
编写编程语言。
Some of the first computer programs
一些最初的计算机程序
were programming languages, so you could actually
是编程语言，所以您实际上可以
program them in a reasonable way.
以合理的方式对它们进行编程。
Whenever you type a variable name the computer doesn't
每当您键入变量名时，计算机都不会
really think about that variable name,
真正考虑那个变量名，
it wants to think about an address in memory.
它想考虑内存中的地址。
And so you've got to translate that variable name
因此，您必须翻译该变量名
into a real, physical address in the machine, or a position
到机器中真实的物理地址或位置
on the stack, or whatever it is in real life.
在堆栈上，或现实生活中的任何东西。
In the old days of Python, I guess
我想在Python的旧时代
this is pre-Python 2 or so, 2.1, I
这是Python 2之前的版本，2.1，我
don't remember the exact transition it was.
不记得那是确切的过渡了。
In the interpreter, there was the dictionary
在口译员那里有字典
of all your global variables, there's
在所有全局变量中，
a dictionary of all your local variables.
所有局部变量的字典。
And that was-- it was right there.
那就是-就在那儿。
I mean you could modify the dictionary,
我的意思是你可以修改字典，
you could do crazy things.
你可以做疯狂的事情。
And all the variables were there.
所有的变量都在那里。
And so they'd match the key to the actual value
因此，它们会将密钥与实际值匹配
stored in the variable.
存储在变量中。
They don't do that anymore because it's a little slow,
他们不再这样做了，因为它有点慢，
but-- and you could do better in practice.
但是，您可以在实践中做得更好。
But at the very least, when you're compiling the thing,
但是至少，当您编译事物时，
you need a dictionary.
你需要一本字典。
And then, later on, you can do more efficient lookups.
然后，以后可以进行更有效的查找。
Let's see.
让我们来看看。
On the internet there are hash tables all over,
互联网上到处都有哈希表，
like in your router.
就像在您的路由器中一样。
Router needs to know all the machines that
路由器需要知道所有的机器
are connected to it.
连接到它。
Each machine has an IP address, so when you get a packet in,
每台机器都有一个IP地址，因此当您收到数据包时，
and it says, deliver to this IP address, you see,
它说，传递到该IP地址，您会看到，
oh, is it in my dictionary of all the machines
哦，在我所有机器的字典中
that are directly connected to me?
与我直接相关？
If so, send it there.
如果是这样，将其发送到那里。
If it's not then it has to find the right subnet.
如果不是，则必须找到正确的子网。
That's not quite a dictionary problem,
那不是字典的问题，
a little more complicated.
稍微复杂一点。
But for looking up local machines, it's a dictionary.
但是对于查找本地计算机，这只是一本字典。
Routers use dictionaries because they need to go really fast.
路由器使用字典是因为它们需要走得很快。
They're getting a billion packets every second.
他们每秒收到十亿个数据包。
Also, in the network stack of a machine,
另外，在机器的网络堆栈中，
when you come in you get it packet delivered
当你进来的时候，你会收到包裹
to a particular port, you need to say, oh, which application,
到特定的端口，您需要说，哦，哪个应用程序，
or which socket is connected to this port?
或哪个插座连接到该端口？
All of these things are dictionaries.
所有这些都是字典。
The point is they're in, basically,
关键是他们进入了
everything you've ever used, virtual memory,
您曾经使用过的所有内容，虚拟内存，
I mean, they're all over the place.
我的意思是，他们到处都是。
There are also some more subtle applications,
还有一些更微妙的应用程序，
where it is not obvious that's it a dictionary,
不明显是字典，
but still, we use this idea of hashing
但是我们仍然使用散列的想法
we're going to talk about today.
我们今天要谈。
Like searching in a string.
就像在字符串中搜索一样。
So when you hit-- I don't know-- in your favorite editor,
因此，当您在您最喜欢的编辑器中点击-不知道时，
you do Control-F, or Control-S, or slash,
您执行Control-F或Control-S或斜杠，
or whatever your way of searching for something
或以任何方式搜寻事物
is, and you type start typing.
是，并且您键入开始键入。
If your editor is clever, it will
如果您的编辑很聪明，它将
use hashing in order to search for that string.
使用散列来搜索该字符串。
It's a faster way to do it.
这是一种更快的方法。
If you use grep, for example, in Unix it does it in a fancy way.
例如，如果您使用grep，则在Unix中它会以一种奇特的方式进行。
Every time you do a Google search
每次您执行Google搜索
it's essentially using this.
它实际上是在使用它。
It's solving this problem.
解决了这个问题。
I don't know what algorithm, but we could guess.
我不知道什么算法，但是我们可以猜测。
Using the algorithms we'll cover in next lecture.
使用算法，我们将在下一堂课中介绍。
It wouldn't surprise me.
这不会令我惊讶。
Also, if you have a couple strings
另外，如果您有几串
and you want to know what they have in common, how similar
你想知道他们有什么共同点，有多相似
they are?
他们是？
Example, you have two DNA strings.
例如，您有两个DNA字符串。
You want to see how similar they are, you use hashing.
您想了解它们的相似程度，可以使用散列。
And you're going to do that in the next problem set, PS4,
您将在下一个问题集PS4中进行此操作，
which goes out on Thursday.
星期四出去。
Also, for things like file and directory synchronization.
同样，用于文件和目录同步。
So on Unix, if you rsync or unison, or, I guess,
因此，在Unix上，如果您进行rsync或统一，或者，我想，
modern day-- these days, Dropbox, MIT
现代-这些天，麻省理工学院的Dropbox
startup-- Whenever you're synchronizing files between two
启动-每当您在两个之间同步文件时
locations, you use hashing to tell
位置，您可以使用散列法来判断
whether a file has changed, or whether a directory has
文件是否已更改，或者目录是否具有
changed.
改变了。
That's a big idea.
那是个好主意。
Fairly modern idea.
相当现代的想法。
And also in cryptography-- this will
而且在密码学中-这将
be a topic of next Tuesday's lecture.
成为下周二演讲的主题。
If you're transferring a file and you
如果您正在传输文件而您
want to check that you actually transferred that file,
想检查您是否确实传输了该文件，
and there wasn't some person in the middle corrupting your file
而且中间没有人破坏您的文件
and making it look like it was what you wanted it to be,
并使它看起来像您想要的那样，
you use something called cryptographic hash functions,
您使用所谓的加密哈希函数
which [INAUDIBLE] will talk about on Tuesday.
[音频不清晰]将在星期二谈论。
So tons of motivation for dictionaries.
因此，大量的词典动机。
Let's actually do it, see how they are done.
让我们实际去做，看看它们是如何完成的。
We're going to start with sort of a very simple straw man,
我们将从一个非常简单的稻草人开始，
and then we're going to improve it until, by the end of today,
然后我们将对其进行改进，直到今天年底，
we have a really good way to solve the dictionary
我们有一个很好的方法来解决字典
problem in constant time for operation.
在恒定的操作时间内出现问题。
So the really simple approach is called a direct access table.
因此，真正简单的方法称为直接访问表。
So it's just a big table, an array.
所以这只是一个大表，一个数组。
You have-- the index into the array is the key.
您拥有-数组的索引是关键。
So, store items in an array, indexed by key.
因此，将项目存储在按键索引的数组中。
And in fact, Python kind makes you think about this
实际上，Python种类会让您考虑一下
because the Python notation for accessing dictionaries
因为用于访问字典的Python表示法
is identical to the notation for accessing arrays.
与访问数组的符号相同。
But with arrays, the keys are restricted
但是对于数组，键是受限制的
to be non-negative integers, 0 through n minus 1.
为非负整数，0到n减1。
So why not just implement it that way?
那么，为什么不以这种方式实施呢？
If your keys happen to be integers
如果您的键碰巧是整数
I could just store all my items in a giant array.
我可以将所有物品存储在一个巨大的阵列中。
So if I just want to store an item here with key 2,
因此，如果我只想用键2在这里存储项目
call that, maybe, item 2, I just put that there.
称之为，也许，第2项，我只是放在那儿。
If I want to store something with key 4
如果我想用钥匙4存放东西
I'll just put it there.
我就把它放在那里。
Everything else is going to be null, or none, or whatever.
其他所有内容都将为null，或者为空，或者其他。
So lots of blank entries.
大量空白条目。
Whatever keys I don't use I'll just put a null value there.
无论我不使用什么键，我都会在其中放置一个空值。
Every key that I want to put into the dictionary
我想放入字典中的每个键
I'll just store it at the corresponding position.
我将其存储在相应的位置。
What's bad about this?
这有什么不好？
Yeah.
是的
AUDIENCE: It's hard to associate something with just an integer.
听众：很难将某事物与一个整数相关联。
PROFESSOR: Hard to associate something with an integer.
教授：很难将某些东西与整数联系起来。
Good.
好。
That's one problem.
那是一个问题。
There's actually two big problems with this structure.
这种结构实际上存在两个大问题。
I want both of them.
我要两个
So bad-- badness number one is keys may not be integers.
太糟糕了-坏处之一是键可能不是整数。
Good.
好。
Another problem.
另一个问题。
Yeah.
是的
AUDIENCE: Possibility of collision.
听众：发生碰撞的可能性。
PROFESSOR: Possibility of collision.
教授：可能发生碰撞。
So here there's no collisions.
因此，这里没有碰撞。
We'll get to collisions in a moment,
我们一会儿就会发生碰撞，
but a collision is when two items
但是碰撞是当两个项目
go to the same slot in this table.
转到此表中的同一插槽。
And we defined the problem so there weren't collisions.
并且我们定义了问题，因此没有碰撞。
We said whenever we insert item with the same key you
我们说过，只要我们插入具有相同键的项目
overwrite whatever is there.
覆盖那里的一切。
So collisions are OK.
所以碰撞就可以了。
They will be a problem in a moment, so save your answer.
暂时会出现问题，请保存您的答案。
Yeah?
是啊
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不清]
PROFESSOR: Running time?
教授：运行时间？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不清]
PROFESSOR: For deletion?
教授：要删除吗？
Actually, running time is going to be great.
实际上，运行时间将会很棒。
If I want to insert-- I mean, I do these operations
如果要插入-我是说，我要执行这些操作
but on array instead of a dictionary.
但使用数组而不是字典。
So if I want insert I just put something there.
因此，如果要插入，请在其中放一些东西。
If I want to delete I just set it to null.
如果要删除，只需将其设置为null。
If I want to search I just go there and see is it null?
如果要搜索，我就去那里看看它是否为空？
Yeah?
是啊
AUDIENCE: It's a gigantic memory hog
听众：这是一个巨大的记忆猪
PROFESSOR: It's gigantic memory hog.
教授：这是巨大的记忆。
I like that phrasing.
我喜欢这样的措辞。
Not always of course.
当然不总是如此。
If it happens that your keys are-- the set of possible keys
如果碰巧您的密钥是-可能的密钥集
is not too giant then life is good.
不是太庞大，那么生活就是美好的。
Let's see If I cannot kill somebody today.
让我们看看我今天是否不能杀死某人。
Oh yes.
哦是的
Very good.
很好。
But if you have a lot of keys, you
但是，如果您有很多钥匙，
need one slot in your array per key.
每个键在阵列中需要一个插槽。
That could be a lot.
可能很多。
Maybe your keys are 64-bit integers.
也许您的密钥是64位整数。
Then you need 264 slots just to store one measly dictionary.
然后，您只需要264个插槽即可存储一本麻将字典。
That's huge.
好大
I guess there's also the running time of initialize that.
我想还有初始化它的运行时间。
But at the very least, you have huge space hog.
但是至少，您有巨大的太空猪。
This is bad.
这不好。
So we're going to fix both of these problems one at a time.
因此，我们将一次解决这两个问题。
First problem we're going to talk about
我们要谈论的第一个问题
is what if your keys aren't integers?
如果您的密钥不是整数怎么办？
Because if your keys aren't integers
因为如果你的钥匙不是整数
you can't use this at all.
您根本无法使用。
So lets at least get something that works.
因此，至少让我们得到一些有用的东西。
And this is a notion called prehashing.
这就是所谓的预哈希处理。
I guess different people call it different things.
我猜不同的人称之为不同的事物。
Unfortunately Python calls it hash.
不幸的是，Python将其称为哈希。
It's not hashing, it's prehashing.
它不是散列，而是预散列。
Emphasized the "pre" here.
这里强调“前置”。
So prehash function maps whatever keys
因此prehash函数会映射任何键
you have to non-negative integers.
您必须使用非负整数。
At this point we're not worrying about how big
在这一点上，我们不必担心有多大
those integers are.
这些整数是。
They could be giant.
他们可能是巨大的。
We're not going to fix the second problem til later.
直到以后，我们都不会解决第二个问题。
First problem is if I have some key, maybe it's a string,
第一个问题是，如果我有一些钥匙，也许是字符串，
it's whatever, it's an object, how do I map it to some integer
无论是什么，都是对象，如何将其映射到某个整数
so I could, at least in principle, put it
所以我至少可以在原则上
in a direct access table.
在直接访问表中。
There's a theoretical answer to how to do this,
如何做到这一点有一个理论上的答案，
and then there's the practical answer. how to do this.
然后是实际的答案。这个怎么做。
I'll start with the mathematical.
我将从数学开始。
In theory, I like this, keys are finite and discrete.
从理论上讲，我喜欢这样，键是有限且离散的。
OK.
好。
We know that anything on the computer
我们知道计算机上的任何东西
could, ultimately, be written down as a string of bits.
最终可以写成一串位。
So a string of bits represents an integer.
因此，一串比特代表一个整数。
So we're done.
至此就完成了。
So in theory, this is easy.
因此，从理论上讲，这很容易。
And we're going to assume in this class,
我们将在本课中假设
because it's sort of a theory class,
因为这有点像理论课
that this is what's happening.
这就是正在发生的事情。
At least for analysis, we're always
至少为了分析，我们总是
going to analyze things as if this is what's happening.
去分析事物，好像这是正在发生的事情。
Now in reality, people don't always do this.
现在实际上，人们并不总是这样做。
In particular-- I'll go somewhere else.
特别是-我会去别的地方。
In Python it's not quite so simple,
在Python中并不是那么简单，
but at least you get to see what's going on.
但至少您可以了解发生了什么。
There's a function called hash, which should be called prehash,
有一个名为hash的函数，应称为prehash，
and it, given an object, it produces
它给定一个对象，它产生
a non-- I'm not sure, actually, if it's non-negative.
非-实际上，我不确定是否为非负数。
It's not a big deal if it has a minus sign because then you
它有负号没什么大不了的，因为那你
could just use this and get rid of the sign.
可以使用它并摆脱标志。
But it maps every object to an integer,
但是它将每个对象映射到一个整数，
or every hashable object, technically.
或每个可哈希对象，从技术上讲。
But pretty much anything can be mapped
但是几乎任何东西都可以映射
to an integer, one way or another.
一个整数或另一种整数。
And so for example, if you given it an integer
例如，如果您给它一个整数
it just returns the integer.
它只是返回整数。
So that's pretty easy.
这很容易。
If you give it a string it does something.
如果给它一个字符串，它将执行某些操作。
I don't know exactly what it does,
我不知道到底是怎么回事
but there are some issues.
但是有一些问题。
For example, hash of this string, backslash 0B
例如，此字符串的哈希，反斜杠0B
is equal to the hash of backslash 0 backslash 0C 64.
等于反斜杠0反斜杠0C 64的哈希值。
It's a little tricky to find these examples,
找到这些示例有点棘手，
but they're out there.
但他们在那里。
And I guess, this is probably the lowest one
我想这可能是最低的
in a certain measure.
在某种程度上。
So it's a concern.
因此，这是一个问题。
In practice you have to be careful about these things
在实践中，您必须小心这些事情
because what you'd like-- in an ideal world,
因为您想要的是-在理想的世界中，
and in the theoretical world-- this prehash function of x,
在理论世界中-x的预哈希函数
if it equals the prehash function of y,
如果它等于y的prehash函数，
this should only happen when x=y,
只有在x = y时才会发生这种情况
when they're the same thing.
当他们是同一件事时。
And equals equal sense, I guess, would be the technical version.
我想，相等的意思是技术版本。
Sadly, in Python this is not quite true.
可悲的是，在Python中这不是真的。
But mostly true.
但是大部分都是真的。
Let's see.
让我们来看看。
If you define a custom object, you may know this,
如果定义自定义对象，您可能会知道，
there is an __hash__ method you can implement,
您可以实现__hash__方法，
which tells Python what to do when you call hash
告诉Python调用哈希时该怎么做
of your object.
你的对象。
If you don't, it uses the default
如果不这样做，它将使用默认值
of id, which is the physical location
id，即实际位置
of your object in memory.
对象在内存中的大小。
So as long as your object isn't moving around in memory
因此只要您的对象不在内存中移动
this is a pretty good hash function
这是一个很好的哈希函数
because no two items occupy the same space in memory.
因为没有两个项目占用相同的内存空间。
So that's just implementation side of things.
因此，这只是实现方面的事情。
Other implementation side of things is in Python,
其他实现方面是在Python中，
well, there's this distinction between objects and keys,
好吧，对象和键之间是有区别的，
I guess you would say.
我想你会说。
You really don't want this prehash function
您真的不想要此prehash函数
to change value.
改变价值。
In, say, a direct access table, if you store--
例如，在直接访问表中，如果您存储-
you take an item, you compute the prehash function
你拿一件东西，你计算prehash函数
of the key in there, and you throw it in, and it says,
里面的钥匙，然后把它扔进去，然后说，
oh, prehash value is four.
哦，哈希值是4。
Then you put it in position four.
然后将其放在第四位。
If that value change, then when you go to search for that key,
如果该值发生变化，那么当您搜索该键时，
and you call prehash of that thing, and if it give you five,
然后你就把那东西叫prehash，如果它给你五个，
you look in position five, and you say, oh, it's not there.
你看着第五位，你说，哦，不在那里。
So prehash really should not change.
因此，prehash确实不应更改。
If you ever implement this function don't mess with it.
如果您实现了此功能，请不要混淆。
I mean, make sure it's defined in such a way
我的意思是，确保以这种方式定义
that it doesn't change over time.
它不会随着时间而改变。
Otherwise, you won't be able to find your items in the table.
否则，您将无法在表格中找到您的商品。
Python can't protect you from that.
Python无法保护您。
This is why, for example, if you have a list,
这就是为什么，例如，如果您有一个列表，
which is a mutable object, you cannot put it into a hash table
这是一个可变对象，您不能将其放入哈希表
as a key value because it would change over time.
作为键值，因为它会随着时间变化。
Potentially, you'd append to the list, or whatever.
您可能会追加到列表中，或其他任何内容。
All right.
好吧。
So hopefully you're reasonably happy with this.
因此，希望您对此感到满意。
You could also think of it is we're
您也可以想到这是我们
going to assume keys are non-negative integers.
假设键是非负整数。
But in practice, anything you have you
但实际上，任何你拥有的东西
can map to an integer, one way or another.
可以以一种或另一种方式映射到整数。
The bigger problem in a certain sense,
从某种意义上说，更大的问题，
or the more interesting problem is reducing space.
或更有趣的问题是减少空间。
So how do we do that?
那么我们该怎么做呢？
This would be hashing.
这将是哈希。
This is sort of the magic part of today's lecture.
这是今天演讲的神奇部分。
In case you're wondering, hashing
如果您想知道，哈希
has nothing to do with hashish.
与大麻无关。
Hashish is a Arabic root word unrelated to the Germanic,
哈希是阿拉伯语的根词，与日耳曼语无关，
which is hachet, I believe.
我相信那是香囊。
Yeah.
是的
Or hacheh-- I guess, something like that.
还是哈切-我猜是这样的。
I'm not very good at German.
我不太会德语。
Which means hatchet.
这意味着柴刀。
OK
好
It's like you take your key, and you cut it up
就像您拿了钥匙，然后把它剪了一样
into little pieces, and you mix them around and cut and dice,
切成小块，然后将它们混合并切块，
and it's like cooking.
就像做饭一样
OK.
好。
What?
什么？
AUDIENCE: Hash browns.
观众：薯饼。
PROFESSOR: Hash browns, for example.
教授：例如，马铃薯煎饼。
Yeah, same root.
是的，相同的根源。
OK.
好。
It's like the only two English words with that kind of hash.
就像只有两个带有这种哈希的英文单词一样。
OK.
好。
In our case, it's a verb, to hash.
在我们的例子中，这是一个动词，要进行哈希处理。
It means to cut into pieces and mix around.
这意味着切成小块并混合在一起。
OK.
好。
That won't really be clear until towards the end of today's
直到今天快要结束时，这才真正变得不清楚
lecture, but we will eventually get
讲座，但我们最终会得到
to the etymology of hashing.
散列的词源。
Or, we've got the etymology, but why it's, actually,
或者，我们有词源，但是为什么呢
why we use that term.
为什么我们使用该术语。
All right.
好吧。
So the big idea is we take all possible keys
因此，最大的想法是我们采用所有可能的钥匙
and we want to reduce them down to some small, small set
我们希望将它们减少到一些小的集合
of integers.
整数
Let me draw a picture of that.
让我画一幅画。
So we have this giant space of all possible keys.
因此，我们拥有所有可能的钥匙的巨大空间。
We'll call this key space.
我们将其称为关键空间。
It's like outer space, basically.
基本上，这就像外太空。
It's giant.
太好了
And if we stored a direct access table,
如果我们存储了直接访问表，
this would also be giant.
这也将是巨大的。
And we don't want to do that.
而且我们不想这样做。
We'd like to somehow map using a hash function h down
我们想以某种方式使用哈希函数h down进行映射
to some smaller set.
到一些较小的集合。
How do I want to draw this?
我要如何绘制？
Like an array.
像数组。
So we're going to have possible values 0 up to m minus 1.
因此，我们将取0到m减去1的可能值。
m is a new thing.
m是新事物。
It's going to be the size of our hash table.
这将是我们的哈希表的大小。
Let's call the hash table.
让我们称之为哈希表。
I think we'll call it t also.
我想我们也称它为t。
And we'd somehow like to map--
我们想以某种方式映射-
All right.
好吧。
So there's a giant space of all possible keys,
因此，所有可能的按键都有巨大的空间，
but then there's a subset of keys that are actually
但是实际上有一部分键
stored in this set, in this dictionary.
存储在此集合中，在此字典中。
At any moment in time there's some set
在任何时候都有一些设置
of keys that are present.
存在的密钥。
That set changes, but at any moment
那个设置改变了，但是在任何时候
there's some keys that are actually there.
实际上有一些键。
k1, k2, k3, k4.
k1，k2，k3，k4。
I'd like to map them to positions in this table.
我想将它们映射到此表中的位置。
So maybe I store k2-- or actually, item 2 would go here.
因此，也许我存储了k2--或实际上，项目2会放在这里。
In particular, this is when h of k2, if it equals zero,
特别是k2的h等于零时
then you'd put item 2 there.
然后将项目2放在那里。
Item 3, let's say, it's at position-- wow,
假设第3项处于正确位置–哇，
3 would be a bit of a coincidence, but what the hell.
3有点巧合，但是到底是什么。
Maybe h or k3 equals 3.
也许h或k3等于3。
Then you'd put item 3 here.
然后，您将项目3放在这里。
OK.
好。
You get the idea.
你明白了。
So these four items each have a special position
所以这四个项目都有一个特殊的位置
in their table.
在他们的桌子上。
And the idea is we would like to be, m to be around n.
我们的想法是，我们希望m在n附近。
n is the number of keys In the dictionary right now.
n是当前词典中的键数。
So if we could achieve that, the size of the table
因此，如果我们能够做到这一点，那么表格的大小
was proportional to the number of keys being stored
与存储的密钥数量成正比
in the dictionary, that would be good news because then
在字典中，那将是个好消息，因为
the space is not gigantic and hoggish.
这个空间不是巨大的，也不是时髦的。
It would just be linear, which is optimal.
它只是线性的，这是最佳的。
So if we want to store m things, maybe we'll
因此，如果我们要存储m个东西，也许我们会
use 2m space, a 3m space, but not much more.
使用2m空间，即3m空间，但不要更多。
How the heck are we going to define such a function h?
我们将如何定义这样的函数h？
Well, that's the rest of the lecture.
好了，这就是本讲座的其余部分。
But even before we define a function h,
但即使在定义函数h之前，
do you see any problems with this?
您看到这个有什么问题吗？
Yeah.
是的
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: Yeah.
教授：是的。
This space over here, this is pigeonhole principle.
这里的空间，这是信鸽原理。
The number of slots for your pigeons over here
您的鸽子在这里的插槽数
is way smaller than the number of possible pigeons.
比可能的鸽子数量少得多。
So there are going to be two keys that
因此，将有两个关键
map to the same slot in the hash table.
映射到哈希表中的相同插槽。
This is what we call a collision.
这就是我们所说的碰撞。
Let's call this, I don't know, ki, kj.
我们称呼它，我不知道，ki，kj。
h of ki equals h of kj, but the keys are different.
ki的h等于kj的h，但是键不同。
So ki does not equal kj, yet their hash functions
所以ki不等于kj，但是它们的哈希函数
are the same, hash values are the same.
相同，哈希值相同。
We call that a collision.
我们称之为碰撞。
And that's guaranteed to happen a lot, yet somehow,
这肯定会发生很多，但是无论如何，
we can still make this work.
我们仍然可以完成这项工作。
That's the magic.
那就是魔术。
And that is going to be chaining.
那将是连锁的。
We've done these guys.
我们已经做了这些家伙。
Next up is a technique for dealing with collisions.
接下来是处理冲突的技术。
There are two techniques for dealing with collisions
有两种处理冲突的技术
we're going to talk about in 006.
我们将在006中讨论。
One is called chaining, and next Tuesday, we'll
一种叫做链接，下周二，我们将
see another method called open addressing.
请参阅另一种称为开放式寻址的方法。
But let's start with chaining.
但是，让我们从链接开始。
The idea with chaining a simple.
用链接的想法很简单。
If you have multiple items here all with the same-- that
如果您在这里有多个相同的项目-
hash to the same position, just store them as a list.
哈希到相同位置，只需将它们存储为列表即可。
I'm going to draw it as a linked list.
我将其绘制为链接列表。
I think I need a big picture here.
我想在这里我需要一幅大图。
So we have our nice universe, various keys that we actually
因此，我们拥有了一个不错的宇宙，实际上我们拥有各种键
have present.
有礼物。
So these are the keys in the dictionary,
这些是字典中的键，
and this is all of key space.
这就是关键空间。
These guys map to slots in the table.
这些家伙映射到表中的插槽。
Some of them might map to the same value.
其中一些可能会映射到相同的值。
So let's say k1 and k2, suppose they collide.
因此，假设k1和k2发生碰撞。
So they both go this slot.
所以他们俩都去这个位置。
What we're going to store here is a linked list
我们要在这里存储的是一个链表
that stores item 1, and stores a pointer
存储项1，并存储指针
to the next item, which is item 2.
到下一个项目，即项目2。
And that's the end of the list.
到此为止。
Or you could-- however you want to draw a null.
或者，您可以-但是您想绘制一个null。
So however many items there are, we're
所以不管有多少东西，我们
going to have a linked list of that length in that slot.
在该广告位中将具有该长度的链表。
So in particular, if there's just one item, like say,
因此，特别是如果只有一项，例如
this k3 here, maybe it just maps to this slot.
这个k3在这里，也许只是映射到这个插槽。
And maybe that's all that maps to that slot.
也许这就是映射到该插槽的全部。
In that case, we just say, follow this item 3,
在这种情况下，我们只是说，遵循第3项，
and there's no other items.
并且没有其他项目。
Some slots are going to be completely empty.
一些插槽将完全是空的。
There nothing there so you just store a null pointer.
那里什么都没有，所以您只存储一个空指针。
That is hashing with chaining.
那就是用链式哈希。
It's pretty simple, very simple really.
这很简单，真的很简单。
The only question is why would you expect it to be any good?
唯一的问题是，您为什么期望它会有什么好处？
Because, in the worst case, if you fix your hash function
因为在最坏的情况下，如果您修复哈希函数
here, h, there's going to be a whole bunch of keys
在这里，h，将有一堆钥匙
that all map to the same slot.
全部都映射到同一个广告位
And so in the worst case, those are the keys that you insert,
因此，在最坏的情况下，这些就是您要插入的键，
and they all go here.
他们都去了这里。
And then you have this fancy data structure.
然后您就拥有了这种奇特的数据结构。
And in the end, all you have is a linked list of all n items.
最后，您所拥有的只是所有n个项目的链表。
So the worst case is theta n.
因此，最坏的情况是theta n。
And this is going to be true for any hashing scheme, actually.
实际上，这对于任何哈希方案都是正确的。
In the worst case, hashing sucks.
在最坏的情况下，哈希很糟糕。
Yet in practice, it works really, really well.
但是实际上，它确实非常好。
And the reason is randomization, essentially,
原因是随机化
that this hash function, unless you're really unlucky,
该哈希函数，除非您真的很不幸，
the hash function will nicely distribute your items,
哈希函数可以很好地分配您的物品，
and most of these lists will have constant length.
并且这些列表中的大多数将具有恒定的长度。
We're going to prove that under an assumption.
我们将在一个假设下证明这一点。
Well have to warm up a little bit.
好吧，要热身一点。
But I'm also going to cop out a little m as you'll see.
但正如您所看到的，我还要弥补一点点。
So in 006 we're going to make an assumption called Simple
因此，在006年，我们将做一个简单的假设
Uniform Hashing.
均匀散列。
OK.
好。
And this is an assumption, it's an unrealistic assumption.
这是一个假设，这是不现实的假设。
I would go so far as to say it's false, a false assumption.
我什至会说这是错误的，是错误的假设。
But it's really convenient for analysis,
但这真的很方便分析，
and it's going to make it obvious
这将使其显而易见
why chaining is a good idea.
为什么链接是一个好主意。
Sadly, the assumption isn't quite true,
可悲的是，这个假设并不完全正确，
but it gives you a flavor.
但它给你一种味道。
If you want to see why hashing is actually good,
如果您想了解为什么哈希实际上很好，
I'm going to hint at it at the end of lecture
我要在课后暗示
but really should take 6.046 Yeah.
但确实应该花6.046对。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE] question.
听众：[听不清]问题。
Is the hashing function [INAUDIBLE]?
哈希函数是[音频不清晰]吗？
Like, how do we know the array is still [INAUDIBLE]?
就像，我们怎么知道数组仍然是[音频不清晰]？
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
The hashing function-- I guess I didn't specify up here.
哈希函数-我想我没有在这里指定。
The hashing function maps your universe to 0, 1,
哈希函数将您的Universe映射为0、1
up to m minus 1, That's the definition.
直到m减1，这就是定义。
So it's guaranteed to reduce the space of keys to just m slots.
因此，可以保证将键的空间减少到仅m个插槽。
So your hashing function needs to know what m is.
因此，您的哈希函数需要知道m是什么。
In reality there's not going to be one hashing function,
实际上，将不会只有一个哈希函数，
there's going to be 1 for each m, or at least one for each m.
每m将有1，或每m至少有1。
And so, depending on how big your table is,
因此，根据您的桌子有多大，
you use the corresponding hash function.
您使用相应的哈希函数。
Yeah, good question.
是的，很好的问题。
So the hash function is what does
那么哈希函数是做什么的
the work of reducing your key space down
减少密钥空间的工作
to small set of slots.
到小型插槽。
So that's what's going to give us low space.
这就是要给我们的空间不足的原因。
OK.
好。
But now, how do we get low time?
但是现在，我们如何获得较少的时间？
Let me just state this assumption and get to business.
让我只陈述这个假设并开始做生意。
Simply, uniform hashing is, essentially,
简单来说，统一哈希本质上是
two probabilistic assumptions.
两个概率假设。
The first one is uniformity.
第一个是均匀性。
If you take some key in your space
如果您在自己的空间拿一些钥匙
that you want to store the hash function
您想要存储哈希函数的
maps it to a uniform random choice.
将其映射到统一的随机选择。
This is, of course, is what you want to happen.
当然，这就是您想要发生的事情。
Each of these slots here is equally likely to be hashed to.
这些插槽中的每个插槽都同样有可能被哈希到。
OK.
好。
That's a good start.
这是一个好的开始。
But to do proper analysis, not only do we uniformity,
但是要进行适当的分析，我们不仅要保持一致，
we also need independence.
我们还需要独立。
So not only is this true for each key individually,
因此，不仅对于每个键都是如此，
but it's true for all the keys together.
但是所有键都正确。
So if key one maps to a uniform random place,
因此，如果密钥一映射到统一的随机位置，
no matter where it goes, key two also
无论走到哪里，关键二也是
matches to a uniform random place.
匹配到统一的随机位置。
And no matter where those two go,
不管那两个去哪
key three maps to a uniform random place.
将三个关键点映射到一个统一的随机位置。
This really can't be true.
这真的不是真的。
But if it's true, we can prove that this takes constant time.
但是，如果这是真的，我们可以证明这需要持续的时间。
So let me do that.
所以让我这样做。
So under this assumption, we can analyze
所以在这个假设下，我们可以分析
hashing-- hashing with chaining is what this method is called.
散列-使用链接的散列称为此方法。
So let's do it
所以做吧
I want to know-- I got to cheat, sorry.
我想知道-我必须作弊，对不起。
I got to remember the notation.
我必须记住这种记法。
I don't have any good notation here.
我在这里没有任何好的记号。
All right.
好吧。
What I'd like to know is the expected length of a chain.
我想知道的是预期的链长。
OK.
好。
Now this is if I have n keys that are stored in the table,
现在，如果我有n个键存储在表中，
and m slots in the table, then what
和表中的m个插槽，然后
is the expected length of a chain?
的预期长度是多少？
Any suggestions.
有什么建议么。
Yeah.
是的
AUDIENCE: 1 over m to the n.
听众：从m到n的1分。
PROFESSOR: 1 over m to the n?
教授：从1到m到n？
That's going to be a probability of something.
那将是某种可能性。
Not quite.
不完全的。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不清]
PROFESSOR: That's between 0 and 1.
教授：介于0和1之间。
It's probably at least one, or something.
它可能至少是一个或类似的东西。
Yeah.
是的
AUDIENCE: m over n.
观众：n对n。
PROFESSOR: n over m, yeah.
教授：是的，胜过m。
It's really easy.
真的很简单。
The chance of a key going to a particular slot is 1 over m.
密钥进入特定插槽的机率是1超过m。
They're all independent, so it's 1 over m, plus 1 over m,
他们都是独立的，所以是1比m加1比m，
plus 1 over m, n times.
在m上加1，n次。
So it's n over m.
所以已经超过m了。
This is really easy when you have independence.
有独立性时，这真的很容易。
Sadly, in the real world, you don't have independence.
可悲的是，在现实世界中，您没有独立性。
We're going to call this thing alpha,
我们将其称为alpha，
and it's also known as the load factor of the table.
并且也称为表格的负载系数。
So if it's one, n equals m.
因此，如果为1，则n等于m。
And so the length of a chain is one.
因此，一条链的长度是一个。
If it's 10, then you have 10 times as many elements
如果是10，则元素的数量是其10倍
as you have slots.
因为你有插槽。
But still, the expected length of a chain is 10.
但仍然，预期的链长为10。
That's a constant.
这是一个常数。
It's OK.
没关系。
If it's a 12, that's OK.
如果是12，就可以了。
It means that you have a bigger table than you have items.
这意味着您的桌子比物品更大。
As long as it's a constant, as long as we have-- I
只要它是常数，只要我们拥有
erased it by now-- as long as m is theta n,
现在将其擦除-只要m为theta n，
this is going to be constant.
这将是恒定的。
And so we need to maintain this property.
因此，我们需要维护此属性。
But as long as you set your table size to the right value,
但是只要您将表格大小设置为正确的值，
to be roughly n, this will be constant.
大约为n，这将是恒定的。
And so the running time of an operation, insert, delete,
因此，操作，插入，删除，
and search-- Well, search is really
搜索-好吧，搜索确实
the hardest because when you want to search for a key,
最难的是因为当您要搜索密钥时，
you map it into your table, then you walk the linked list
您将其映射到表格中，然后遍历链表
and look for the key that you're searching for.
并查找您要搜索的密钥。
Now is this the key you're searching for?
现在这是您要搜索的键吗？
No, it's not the key you're searching for.
不，这不是您要寻找的钥匙。
Is this the key you're searching for?
这是您要寻找的钥匙吗？
Those are not the keys you're searching for.
这些不是您要搜索的键。
You keep going.
你继续前进。
Either you find your key or you don't.
您找到钥匙还是找不到钥匙。
But in the worst case, you have to walk the entire list.
但是在最坏的情况下，您必须遍历整个列表。
Sorry for the bad Star Trek reference-- Star Wars.
对不起，《星际迷航》的参考文献-《星球大战》。
God.
神。
I'm not awake.
我还没醒
All right.
好吧。
In general, the running time, in the worst case,
一般来说，最坏情况下的运行时间
is 1 plus the length of your chain.
是1加上您的链的长度。
OK.
好。
So it's going to be 1 plus alpha.
因此它将是1加alpha。
Why do I write one?
我为什么要写一个？
Well, because alpha can be much smaller than 1, in general.
好吧，因为alpha通常可以小于1。
And you always have to pay the cost
而且你总是要付出代价
of computing the hash function.
哈希函数的计算。
We're going to assume that takes constant time.
我们将假设这需要固定的时间。
And then you have to follow the first pointer.
然后，您必须遵循第一个指针。
So you always pay constant time, but then you also pay alpha.
因此，您始终要支付固定的时间，但同时您也要支付Alpha。
That's your expected life.
那就是你的预期寿命。
OK.
好。
That's the analysis.
那就是分析。
It's super simple.
非常简单。
If you assume Simple Uniform Hashing,
如果您假设“简单统一哈希”，
it's clear, as long as your load factor is constant, m theta n,
很明显，只要您的负载系数是常数，
you get constant running time for all your operations.
您可以在所有操作中获得恒定的运行时间。
Life is good.
生活很好。
This is the intuition of why hashing works.
这就是为什么哈希起作用的直觉。
It's not really why hashing works.
这并不是散列起作用的真正原因。
But it's about as far as we're going to get in 006.
但这大约是我们将要获得的006。
I'm going to tell you a little bit more
我要告诉你更多
about why hashing is actually good to practice and in theory.
关于为什么哈希实际上在实践上和理论上都很好的问题。
What are we up to?
我们在忙什么呢？
Last topic is hash functions.
最后一个主题是哈希函数。
The one remaining thing is how do I construct h?
剩下的一件事是如何构造h？
How do I actually map from this giant universe of keys
我实际上是如何从这个巨大的按键范围映射的
to this small set of slots in the table, there's m of them?
在桌子上的这小部分插槽中，有m个？
I'm going to give you three hash functions, two of which are,
我将为您提供三个散列函数，其中两个是
let's say, common practice, and the third of which is actually
比方说，通常的做法，其中三分之一是
theoretically good.
理论上很好。
So the first two are not good theoretically.
因此，前两个理论上并不理想。
You can prove that they're bad, but at least they
您可以证明它们不好，但是至少它们
give you some flavor, and they're
给你一些味道，他们是
still common in practice because a lot of the time they're OK,
在实践中仍然很常见，因为很多时候他们还可以，
but you can't really prove much about them.
但是您无法真正证明它们。
OK.
好。
So first method, sort of the obvious one,
所以第一种方法，很明显，
called the division method.
称为除法。
And if you have a key, this could
如果您有一把钥匙，这可能
be a giant key, huge universe of keys,
成为一个巨大的钥匙，巨大的钥匙宇宙，
you just take that key, modulo m,
你只要拿那个钥匙，取模m，
that gives you a number between zero and m minus 1.
给您一个介于0到m减1之间的数字。
Done.
做完了
It's so easy.
它是如此容易。
I'm not going to tell you in detail
我不会详细告诉你
why this is a bad method.
为什么这是一个不好的方法。
Maybe you can think about it.
也许您可以考虑一下。
It's especially bad if m has some common factors with k.
如果m与k有一些公因数，这尤其糟糕。
Like, let's say k is even always,
例如，假设k始终是
and m is even also because you say,
m甚至还因为你说，
oh, I'd like a table the size of power of two.
哦，我想要一张有2的幂的表。
That seems natural.
看起来很自然。
Then that will be really bad because you'll
那真的很不好，因为你会
use only half the table.
只使用一半的桌子。
There are lots of situations where this is bad.
在很多情况下，这是不好的。
In practice, it's pretty good.
在实践中，这非常好。
If m is prime, you always choose a prime table size,
如果m为质数，则始终选择质数表大小，
so you don't have those common factors.
因此您没有那些共同的因素。
And it's not very close to a power of 2 or power of 10
而且它不是非常接近2的幂或10的幂
because real world powers of 2's and 10's are common.
因为现实世界中2和10的幂很常见。
But it's very hackish, OK?
但这很骇人，好吗？
It works a lot of the time but not always.
它在很多时候都有效，但并非总是如此。
A cooler method-- I think it's cooler-- still,
更酷的方法-我认为它更酷-
you can't prove much about it-- Division didn't
你不能证明太多-部门没有
seem to work so great, so how about multiplication?
看起来效果很好，那么乘法呢？
What does that mean?
这意味着什么？
Multiply by m, that wouldn't be very good.
乘以m，那不是很好。
Now, it's a bit different.
现在，有点不同了。
We're going to take the key, multiply it by an integer, a,
我们要拿钥匙，乘以一个整数，
and then we're going to do this crazy, crazy stuff.
然后我们将要做这些疯狂的事情。
Take it mod 2 to the w and then shift it right, w minus r.
将mod 2取到w，然后右移w减去r。
OK.
好。
What is w?
什么是w？
We're assuming that we're in a w-bit machine.
我们假设我们在w位计算机中。
Remember way back in models of computation?
还记得计算模型的历史吗？
Your machine has a word size, it's w bits.
您的计算机的字大小为w位。
So let's suppose it's w bits.
因此，我们假设它是w位。
So we have our key, k.
所以我们有密钥k。
Here it is.
这里是。
It's w bits long.
它长w位。
We take some number, a-- think of a as being
我们取一些数字，a-认为是
a random integer among all possible w bit integers.
所有可能的w位整数中的一个随机整数。
So it's got some zeros, it's got some ones.
所以它有一些零，有一些零。
And I multiply these.
我乘以这些。
What does multiplication mean in binary?
乘法在二进制中是什么意思？
Well, I take one of these copies of k for each one that's here.
好吧，我在这里为每个k取一份k的副本。
So I'm going to take one copy here
所以我要在这里拿一份
because there's a one there.
因为那里有一个。
I'm going to take one copy here because there's a one there.
我要在这里拿一本，因为那里有一本。
And I'm going to take one copy here
我要在这里复印一份
because there's a one there.
因为那里有一个。
And on average, half of them will be ones.
平均而言，其中一半会是。
So I have various copies of k, and then I just add them up.
所以我有k的各种副本，然后我将它们加起来。
And you know, stuff happens.
而且，事情发生了。
I get some gobbledygook here.
我在这里有些傻瓜。
OK.
好。
How big is it?
它有多大？
In general, it's two words long.
通常，这是两个字长。
When I multiply two words I get two words.
当我将两个单词相乘时，我得到两个单词。
It could be twice as long, in general.
通常，它的长度可能是它的两倍。
And what this business is doing is saying take the right word,
而这项业务正在做的是说正确的话，
this right half here-- let the right word in, I guess,
这右边的一半-我猜，请输入正确的词，
if you see vampire movies-- and then shift
如果您看到吸血鬼电影-然后移
right-- this is a shift right operation-- by w minus r.
右-这是右移操作-由w减r。
I didn't even say what r is.
我什至没有说r是什么。
But basically, what I want is these bits.
但基本上，我想要的是这些位。
I want r bits here-- this is w bits.
我要在这里r位-这是w位。
I want the leftmost r bits of the rightmost w bits
我想要最右边的w位中最左边的r位
because I shift right here and get rid of all these guys.
因为我现在就转移到这里，摆脱所有这些家伙。
r-- I should say, m, is two to the r.
r--我应该说，m是r的2。
So I'm going to assume here I have
所以我要假设我有
a table of size a power of 2, and then this number will
一个大小为2的幂的表，然后此数字将
be a number between 0 and m minus 1.
为0到m减1之间的数字。
OK.
好。
Why does this work?
为什么这样做？
It's intuitive.
很直观
In practice it works quite well because what you're
在实践中，效果很好，因为您是
doing is taking a whole bunch of sort of randomly
做的是随机抽取一大堆
shifted copies of k, adding them up-- you get carries,
转移k的副本，将其加起来-您可以随身携带，
things get mixed up-- This is hashing.
事情变得混乱了-这是哈希。
This is-- you're taking k, sort of cutting it up
这是-您要提取k，将其切开
while you're shifting it around, adding things and they collide,
当您移动它，添加东西而它们碰撞时，
and weird stuff happens.
和奇怪的事情发生。
You sort of randomize stuff.
您有点随机化的东西。
Out here, you don't get much randomization
在这里，您不会得到太多随机化
because most-- like the last bit could just
因为大多数-就像最后一点一样
be this one bit of k.
是k的这一位。
But in the middle, everybody's kind of colliding together.
但是在中间，每个人都在相互碰撞。
And so intuitively, you're mixing
因此，直观地讲，您在混音
lots of things in the center.
中心有很多东西。
You take those r bits, roughly, in the center.
您大致将这些r位放在中间。
That will be nicely mixed up.
那会很好地混合在一起。
And most of the time this works well.
而且在大多数情况下，这种方法效果很好。
In practice it works well-- I have some things written here.
实际上，它运作良好-我在这里写了一些东西。
a better be odd, otherwise you're throwing away stuff.
更好的是奇怪，否则您将扔掉东西。
And it should not be very close to a power of 2.
而且它不应该非常接近2的幂。
But it should be in between 2 to the r minus 1 and 2 to the r.
但是它应该在2到r减1和2到r之间。
Cool.
凉。
One more.
多一个。
Again, theoretically, this can be bad.
同样，从理论上讲，这可能是不好的。
And I leave it as an exercise to find situations, find
我将其作为发现情况，发现问题的练习
key values where this does not do a good job.
不能很好地完成的关键值。
The cool method is called universal hashing.
很酷的方法称为通用哈希。
This is something that's a bit beyond the scope of 006.
这超出了006的范围。
If you want to understand it better you should take 046.
如果您想更好地理解它，则应该采取046。
But I'll give you the flavor and the method, one of the methods.
但是，我会给您介绍其中一种方法和风味。
There's actually many ways to do this.
实际上有很多方法可以做到这一点。
We see a mod m on the outside.
我们在外面看到一个mod m。
That's just division method just to make the number between 0
那只是使数字介于0之间的除法
and a minus 1.
和减1。
Here's our key.
这是我们的钥匙。
And then there's these numbers a and b.
然后是这些数字a和b。
These are going to be random numbers between 0
这些将是0之间的随机数
and p minus 1.
和p减1。
What's p?
什么是p？
Prime number bigger than the size of the universe.
质数大于宇宙的大小。
So it's a big prime number.
因此，这是一个很大的素数。
I think we know how to find prime numbers.
我认为我们知道如何找到质数。
We don't know in this class, but people
我们这堂课不知道，但是人们
know how to find the prime numbers.
知道如何找到素数。
So there's a subroutine here, find a big prime number
所以这里有一个子程序，找到一个大素数
bigger than your universe.
比宇宙还大
It's not too hard to do that.
做到这一点并不难。
We can do it in polynomial time.
我们可以在多项式时间内完成。
That's just set up.
这就是设置。
You do that once for a given size table.
对于给定的尺寸表，只需执行一次。
And then you choose two random numbers, a and b.
然后选择两个随机数a和b。
And then this is the hash function, a times k
然后是哈希函数，乘以k
plus b, mod p mod m.
加b，mod p mod m。
OK.
好。
What does this do?
这是做什么的？
It turns out-- here's the interesting part.
事实证明-这是有趣的部分。
For worst case keys, k1 and k2, that are distinct,
对于最差的情况，密钥k1和k2是截然不同的，
the probability of h of k1 equaling h of k2 is 1 over n.
k1的h等于k2的h的概率是n的1。
So probability of two keys that are different colliding
所以两个不同碰撞的钥匙的概率
is 1 over m, for the worst case keys.
在最坏的情况下，m大于1。
What the heck does that mean?
这是什么意思？
What's the probability over?
几率超过多少？
Any suggestions?
有什么建议么？
What's random here?
这是随机的吗？
AUDIENCE: a and b.
听众：a和b。
PROFESSOR: a and b.
教授：a和b。
This is the probability over a and b.
这是在a和b上的概率。
This is the probability over the choice of your hash function.
这是选择哈希函数的概率。
So it's the worst case inputs, worst case insertions,
因此，这是最坏情况的输入，最坏情况的插入，
but random hash function.
但是随机哈希函数。
As long as you choose your random hash function,
只要您选择随机哈希函数，
the probability of collision is 1 over m.
碰撞的概率是1超过m。
This is the ideal situation
这是理想的情况
And so you can prove, just like we analyzed here--
因此您可以证明，就像我们在这里进行的分析一样-
It's a little more work.
还有更多工作。
It's in the notes.
在笔记中。
You use linearity of expectation.
您使用期望线性。
And you can prove, still, that the expected length
您仍然可以证明预期长度
of a chain-- the expected number of collisions that a key has
链的数量-密钥发生的预期碰撞次数
with another key is the load factor, in the worst case,
另一个关键是负载系数，在最坏的情况下，
but in expectation for a given hash function.
但期望有一个给定的哈希函数。
So still, the expected length of a chain,
因此，预期的链长
and therefore, the expected running time
因此，预期的运行时间
of hashing with chaining, using this hash function,
使用此哈希函数进行链式哈希处理，
or this collection of hash functions, or a randomly chosen
或此哈希函数集合，或随机选择
one, is constant for constant load factor.
第一，对于恒定的负载系数是恒定的。
And that's why hashing really works in theory.
这就是散列理论上真正起作用的原因。
We're not going to go into details of this again.
我们将不再赘述。
Take 6.046 if you want to know.
如果您想知道，请取6.046。
But this should make you feel more comfortable.
但这应该会让您感到更舒适。
And we'll see other ways do hashing next class.
我们将看到其他方法对下一个类进行哈希处理。